# Abdi Bekele

# **FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

Email | GitHub | LinkedIn | Portofolio

#### **SUMMARY**

As a full-stack software developer, my passion lies in leveraging JavaScript, React, Redux, and Ruby on Rails to produce clean, well-structured, and secure code. I prioritize designs that are accessible to all users. I have significant experience in pair programming and remote work, and my proficiency in swiftly grasping and implementing new technologies contributes to my consistent ability to maintain high levels of productivity and efficiency in my work

#### **SKILLS**

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, SCSS, Tailwind, HTML5, CSS3

**Back-End:** Node.js, Ruby, Rails, MySQL, PostgreSQL **Programming Language:** C++, Java, JavaScript and Ruby

Tools & Methods: Unit and Integration Testing, Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development,

RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools, Linux, Postman

**Professional:** Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

#### **EXPERIENCE**

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

February 2022 - Present

- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews, leading to a 95% completion rate of the program.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to enhance code quality and overall performance by 20%.
- Offered guidance on motivation, resulting in a 10% increase in student retention and program completion rates.
- Facilitated group discussions and Q&A sessions, resulting in a 50% increase in performance and promoting collaboration and knowledge sharing among students.

## **Ethiopia Electricity Utility**

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Computer Engineer (Intern)

June 2022 - November 2022

- Developed a billing app using Flutter, which resulted in a 25% increase in efficiency.
- Collaborated with senior developers to gather requirements, identify technical constraints, and develop project plans, resulting in a 40% increase in my skills.
- Maintained and updated existing software systems, implemented new features, and fixed bugs, resulting in a 25% improvement in the code.
- Stayed up-to-date with emerging trends and technologies in mobile application development and shared my knowledge with team members to promote continuous learning and improvement, resulting in a 90% increase in knowledge sharing.

## HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote Full Stack Web Development

December 2022 - Present

Proficiently mastering intermediate and advanced front-end development topics such as React, Redux, Git, and DS&A challenges, while building multiple projects independently and through pair programming, and also acquiring expertise in backend development using Node.js, Ruby, Rails, and Postgres, has resulted in a comprehensive skill set capable of tackling diverse software development challenges.

**Bookstore:** A website app that allows users to add books by author, title, and category on an API. Users can leave comments on books they have read, edit, or delete their comments.

**Space Travellers' Hub**: Web app for a space travel company, integrating with SpaceX API for real-time data, allowing users to reserve rockets and join curated space missions.

**Meal App:** A web App with API integration for interactive features like liking, commenting, and a pop-up displaying ingredient details of selected meals.

**Doctor Appointment App:** A website offers a user-friendly platform for patients to register, log in, set appointments, check doctor profiles, and manage their appointments. Admins can effortlessly add or delete doctors and monitor the platform, ensuring seamless healthcare access and efficient management.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### ADDIS ABABA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

Computer Engineering Degree

January 2018 - July 2023

**Library Management System**: The software application, built using PHP and MySQL, is feature-rich and user-friendly. It facilitates seamless cataloging, tracking, and administration of library resources, circulation, and member details through an intuitive interface, allowing for effortless access and exploration of library materials.

**ATM Machine:** This robust and secure software system, developed using the C++ language, provides users with an intuitive and user-friendly interface for performing various banking transactions, including withdrawals, deposits, and balance inquiries.

#### CISCO CENTER

CCNAv7

September 2022 - September 2023

 Applied my skills and knowledge gained from CCNA to various networking projects using tools such as Packet Tracer and GNS3. These projects involved network configuration, device management, switching, routing, enterprise networking, security, and automation.

# **MICROVERSE**

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full-Time

September 2022 - Present

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with HTML, CSS, different CSS frameworks, JavaScript, React, Redux, Ruby, Ruby on Rail, and Postgres.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.